The Catalogue of Britten Manuscripts: Musical compositions of Benjamin Britten
British Library
- Benjamin Britten: Juvenilia, 1925; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60624-60625; 2 manuscript notebooks
  - Benjamin Britten: 'Violin Sonata in D Major', 1925; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60625; 1 notebook (ii + 17 folios)
    'Trio' scored in ink (ff. 6v-7)
    struck-through passages, in ink and in pencil (ff. 7-9v), including (f. 9-9v) a fragment in full score for different instrumentation
    'Rondo' scored in pencil (ff. 10-14), finishing on f. 13v which is signed and dated
    Sonata violin part, scored in ink (ff. 15-17), signed and dated on f. 17.
    Re-bound (sewn) music manuscript notebook (A. Weekes & Co. Ltd., 14 Hanover St, London), with original soft covers. Dimensions: 295 x 240 mm.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60625
    Christopher Mark, Early Benjamin Britten: A Study of Stylistic and Technical Evolution (1995), p. 10, notes that the 'scherzo' (ff. 5-6) is an arrangement of Waltz 6 from '10 Walztes' (Add MS 60624). Four extracts from the Sonata are published in Mark, Appendix I, pp. 291-5.
- Benjamin Britten: Purcell realisations, [1943-1945]; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60626; 1 volume (9 folios)
  Three realisations of music by Henry Purcell. None of the manuscripts is dated.
  1. Henry Purcell, 'The Golden Sonata' (Z 810), realised for two violins, cello and piano. Entitled 'Sonata IX', scored in pencil with Britten's signature on f. 1 (ff. 1-7v).
  First performance: 21 November 1945, Wigmore Hall, London.
  2. Henry Purcell, 'There's not a swain of the plain' (Z 587), scored in pencil, text over-written in blue ink, with Britten's initials: 'Purcell arr BB' (f. 8).
  Text by Anthony Henley, inserted by Purcell (1693) into John Fletcher, Rule a Wife and Have a Wife (1624). Britten's arrangement was first performed by Britten and Peter Pears: 19 July 1943, Mayflower Barn, Jordans, Buckinghamshire.
  3. Henry Purcell, 'Turn then thine eyes' (Z 425; text Anon). 'Purcell arr BB', scored in pencil (ff. 8v-9).
  First performance (Britten and Pears): 13 March 1945, Salle de l'Ancien Conservatoire, Paris.
  A note in pencil on the fly leaf (by Philip Reed, 3 June 1987) states that the manuscript has been incorrectly bound and indicates what the sequence of folios should be.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60626